A Guide to the McCoy Family Papers, 1787-1882
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
McCoy Family Papers, 1787-1882
Library of Virginia
30194
25 leaves, negative photostats
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by Emmett McCoy of McCoy Virginia, through J. Tracy, III, RFD #5, Box 258, Charlottesville, Virginia, 26 June 1978.
Biographical/Historical Information
The McCoy family was a prominent family that lived in Montgomery County, Virginia. Richard McCoy (d. 1793) had at least two sons, William McCoy and George McCoy. William McCoy and his wife Catherine McCoy were probably the parents of Henry McCoy (ca. 1805-1873). Henry McCoy and his wife Catherine McCoy (b. ca. 1820) had seven children, six of whom lived to inherit property from their father: Francis M. McCoy (b. 1841), George A. McCoy (b. 1843); Amacetta McCoy Linkous (b. ca. 1846), Cynthia McCoy Kissinger (b. ca. 1847), William Henry J. McCoy (b. 1850), and Mary C. McCoy Surface (b. 1857).
Scope and Content
Papers, 1787-1882, of the McCoy family of Montgomery County, Virginia, consisting of correspondence, deeds, plats, receipts, and tax records. Deeds, plats, receipts, and tax records concern property in Montgomery County granted to, purchased by, or sold by members of the McCoy family. Correspondence contains a letter, 23 April 1864, from S. E. M[cCoy?] to an unknown recipient concerning personal matters.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Plat, 8 March 1787, for 2500 acres in Montgomery County, Virginia, for Henry Banks who was issued a patent 27 May 1795., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Plat, June 1812, for 400 acres in Montgomery County of William McCoy and George McCoy, heirs of Richard McCoy., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Deed, 18 December 1826, for 100 acres in Montgomery County from Anthony Plimale of Ohio to William McCoy of Montgomery County. Verified in Giles County, Virginia, 6 March 1827., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Deed, [9 April 1827], from Preston's trustee to [William?] McCoy, incomplete. Deed can be found in Montgomery County Deed Book I-J, pp. 492-493., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Deed, [1829], for 99 3/4 acres in Montgomery County from William McCoy and his wife Susanna McCoy and George McCoy and his wife Patsey McCoy to the heirs of Philip Harless, Michael Pickle assignee. Recorded in Giles County Court August 1829., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Receipt, 6 October 1845, from Levi A. McCoy to Henry McCoy for payment of $66.66 for land sold to Henry McCoy., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Deed, 31 January 1846, for 170 acres in Montgomery County from Joseph Dan and Catherine Dan to Henry McCoy, recorded in Montgomery County 18 June 1846., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Letter, 23 April 1864, from Miss S. E. M[cCoy?] to an unknown recipient concerning personal matters., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Tax record, 27 July 1866, for land in Montgomery County being charged to William McCoy's rept., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Deed, 1 April 1871, for land in Montgomery County from Henry McCoy and Catherine McCoy to Francis M. McCoy. Recorded in Montgomery County 13 August 1872., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Deed of partition, 23 August 1882, between George A. and Mary C. McCoy, Francis M. and Susan E. McCoy, William Henry J. and Louisa E. McCoy, Kyle and Amaretta Linkiris, Andrew and Cynthia Kissinger, and Lemuel and Mary C. Surface as heirs of Henry McCoy. Verified in Giles County 30 August 1882., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Plat, n.d., incomplete., 1 leaf, negative photostat.
- Deed, n.d., incomplete., 2 leaves, negative photostats.